# **LOVESH DONGRE**

## Computer Science Engineer

I am a passionate software development engineer with strong technical ability and am motivated to achieve results in a fast-paced environment! I have good communication skills and am an excellent team player! I have 13 months of experience as an intern and ongoing 6+ months of experience in TCS.

- https://loveshdongre.github.io
- https://github.com/loveshdongre
- □ loveshdongre57@gmail.com
- in https://linkedin.com/in/loveshdongre
- à https://stackoverflow.com/u/10917226

## **EXPERIENCE**

Backend Developer

7/2021 - current

#### **Tata Consultancy Services, Pune**

Tech: Nodejs, Salesforce, ISML, javascript

- · developing one of Japan's biggest ecommerce platform
- Automated deployment process which reduced time to 4
  mins instead of 30 mins
- Provided fast and efficient solution to new requirements (top performers)
- O UI/UX Developer

12/2019 - 01/2020

#### National Informatics Centre, Delhi

Tech: HTML, CSS, JS, Adobe XD

- Redesigned & developed the homepage which improved
   User Experience and overall interface
- · Built design prototypes with best design practices
- O Backend Developer

06/2019 - 07/2019

## HackerKernel, Bhopal

Tech: Nodejs, Sequelize, Handlebars

- · Built the admin analytics dashboard
- · Made CRUD APIs for web app
- Designed the database
- Full Stack Developer

07/2018 - 03/2019

## Danish Housing Society Pvt ltd, Bhopal

Tech: Nodejs, Sequelize, Handlebars

- · Built the admin analytics dashboard
- Made CRUD APIs for web app
- · Designed the database

## Skills / Concepts

Java EE , Javascript, Python, C/C++, SQL, Data structures,
Algorithms , Problem solving , Object Oriented Design (OOPS),
Collections , DBMS , JSP, Servlet , Ajax , Nodejs , HTML , CSS ,
SCSS , Git , MVC , Linux , Windows , Adobe XD , figma,
Communication, Team player, REST API, bootstrap, material ui,
selenium , linux, MySQL, Agile, Test Driven Development

#### **Awards**

Marker Cup

## Delhi Public School, Bhopal

Scored the highest marks (99.4%) in CS (11th Standard)

O 2nd Place in Code adept 2.0

**UIT RGPV, Bhopal** 

Competed against 300 coders in college

## **Projects**

Machine Learning & Web app

### Automation tool for fetching college result in bulk

Tech: Python, Django, Angular, Tensorflow, Selenium, ImgLabel

- An ML automation tool for downloading result of students (5sec/student)
- Created an image classifier to decrypt CAPTCHA images by making a custom dataset (98% accuracy)
- Data Visualization & report generation in pdf and excel
- O Full Stack Java EE Web app

### **Music Player**

Tech: Java EE, JSP, Servlets, Ajax, CSS, Javascript, HTML

- Web app for streaming music
- · enabled uninterrupted music while browsing using Ajax
- · user login functionality enabled
- Web apps (Volunteer)

#### Covolution: college tech fest web apps

Tech: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax

- · Developed front end page for the tech fest website
- · Developed 3 puzzles web app for final round of an event
- Designed the database
- O Browser Extension

#### **Leetcode Enhancer**

Tech: HTML, CSS, JS

- Developed Cross-browser extension for leetcode.com
- · Improves User Experience of coders while coding
- 1400+ downloads (Chrome, Firefox, Edge)
- VR house furnishing android app

#### VR house furnishing via bluetooth controller

Tech: Unity 3D, C#, Sqlite

- Wrote custom driver for bluetooth controller to support windows and android
- · Allow user to select, resize and move furniture of choice
- · Created VR UI components for the virtual environment

## **Education**

<ul><li>B.Tech (Computer Science)</li></ul>	05/2017 - 05/2021
UIT RGPV, Bhopal	86.3%
O Class 12th	03/2016 - 03/2017
Delhi Public School, Bhopal	88.6%
O Class 10th	03/2014 - 03/2015
Delhi Public School, Bhopal	83.6%